<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Group on</title><link>https://atlas-vis.github.io/docs/group/</link><description>Recent content in Group on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://atlas-vis.github.io/docs/group/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Group</title><link>https://atlas-vis.github.io/docs/group/group/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-vis.github.io/docs/group/group/</guid><description>Subclasses: Scene, Collection, Glyph
The Group class represents a group of graphical objects (i.e., marks or groups). To create a group, use the group method in the Scene class, for example:
let g = scene.group(); Properties property explanation type default value id the unique id of the group String type the type of the group String &amp;ldquo;group&amp;rdquo; dataScope the data scope of the group DataScope undefined layout the layout of the group children Layout undefined children the graphical objects in the group Array [] firstChild the first child in the group Mark or Group lastChild the last child in the group Mark or Group bounds the bounding rectangle of the group Rectangle center the center of the group bounds Point x the x coordinate of the center of the group bounds Number y the y coordinate of the center of the group bounds Number visibility whether the group is visible (&amp;ldquo;visible&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;hidden&amp;rdquo;) String &amp;ldquo;visible&amp;rdquo; Methods method explanation return type addChild(c) adds an object to the group void addChildAt(c, i) adds an object to the group at the specified index void contains(x, y) whether this group contains a point</description></item><item><title>Scene</title><link>https://atlas-vis.github.io/docs/group/scene/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-vis.github.io/docs/group/scene/</guid><description>extends Group
The Scene class represents the top-level container in a visualization. This is where graphical objects (i.e., mark or group) are created, transformed and joined with data. To create a scene object, use the scene function:
let scene = atlas.scene(); Properties property explanation type default value fillColor the background color of the scene Color &amp;ldquo;white&amp;rdquo; Properties inherited from Group property explanation type default value id the unique id of the group String type the type of the group String &amp;ldquo;scene&amp;rdquo; children the graphical objects in the group Array [] firstChild the first child in the group Mark or Group bounds the bounding rectangle of the group Rectangle center the center of the group bounds Point Methods: Create Mark or Group method explanation return type mark(type, props) create a new mark with the specified type and properties</description></item><item><title>Collection</title><link>https://atlas-vis.github.io/docs/group/collection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 13:59:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-vis.github.io/docs/group/collection/</guid><description>extends Group
The Collection class represents a group of marks, glyphs, or collections (i.e., nested collection). Children inside a collection have the same &amp;ldquo;type&amp;rdquo; property. Collections are created through the repeat, divide, and densify methods in the Scene class.
Properties inherited from Group property explanation type default value id the unique id of the group String type the type of the group String &amp;ldquo;collection&amp;rdquo; dataScope the data scope of the group DataScope undefined layout the layout of the group children Layout undefined children the graphical objects in the group Array [] firstChild the first child in the group Mark or Group lastChild the last child in the group Mark or Group bounds the bounding rectangle of the group Rectangle center the center of the group bounds Point x the x coordinate of the center of the group bounds Number y the y coordinate of the center of the group bounds Number visibility whether the group is visible (&amp;ldquo;visible&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;hidden&amp;rdquo;) String &amp;ldquo;visible&amp;rdquo; Methods inherited from Group method explanation return type addChild(c) adds an object to the group void addChildAt(c, i) adds an object to the group at the specified index void contains(x, y) whether this group contains a point</description></item><item><title>Glyph</title><link>https://atlas-vis.github.io/docs/group/glyph/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 15:21:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://atlas-vis.github.io/docs/group/glyph/</guid><description>extends Group
The Glyph class represents a group of primitive marks. To create a glyph object, use the glyph method in the Scene class.
Properties inherited from Group property explanation type default value id the unique id of the group String type the type of the group String &amp;ldquo;glyph&amp;rdquo; dataScope the data scope of the group DataScope undefined layout the layout of the group children Layout undefined children the graphical objects in the group Array [] firstChild the first child in the group Mark lastChild the last child in the group Mark or Group bounds the bounding rectangle of the group Rectangle center the center of the group bounds Point x the x coordinate of the center of the group bounds Number y the y coordinate of the center of the group bounds Number visibility whether the group is visible (&amp;ldquo;visible&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;hidden&amp;rdquo;) String &amp;ldquo;visible&amp;rdquo; Methods inherited from Group method explanation return type addChild(c) adds an object to the group void addChildAt(c, i) adds an object to the group at the specified index void contains(x, y) whether this group contains a point</description></item></channel></rss>